GABRIELLA DE FRANCESCO

425-241-0958 | Washington, D.C. | gabriella.defrancesco@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/gabriella-m-defrancesco/

Profile

Full-stack software engineer skilled in Git, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, Django, Node, Express, React, MongoDB, SQL, problemsolving, planning, modeling, and maintaining applications with client-API architectures. Experience working in teams and independently to build functioning sites that solve real-world business problems.

Relevant Experience

Software Engineering Immersive

03/2019 - 06/2019

General Assembly, Washington, DC

Completed a 12-week, 480 hour immersive course applying full-stack software engineering skills to group and individual projects including:

- Developed an interactive memory game using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- Built and deployed a JSON API with RESTful routes and CRUD functionality.
- Developed a full-stack app in collaboration with a team using GitHub and Slack.
 Technologies included MongoDB,
 Mongoose, Express, React, CSS, and Node.
 Responsibilities included creating components and routes on the front-end, developing wireframes, CSS styling, and deploying the application with Heroku.
- Designed a full-stack e-commerce site with mapping and image uploading functionality through the use of APIs.

Software Trainer

06/2013 - 10/2013

ScribesSTAT, Bellingham, WA

- Trained medical professionals to use medical record application software.
- Answering user inquiries regarding computer software and hardware operation.
- Demonstrated patience and attention to detail with the newly implemented electronic medical record software and users.

Skills

HTML5 / CSS 3
Bootstrap
JavaScript / ES6+
jQuery
MongoDB / Mongoose
Express
React
Node.js
Python
PostgreSQL
Git/GitHub

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Creative Writing

09/2013 - 12/2015

Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA

- 3.5 GPA
- Minor in Psychology
- Coursework in Technical Writing & Editing

Work History

English Teacher

07/2018 - 03/2019

Self-Employed, Fairfax, VA

Care Manager

02/2017 - 10/2018

Aegis Living, Bellevue, WA

Administrative Assistant 02/2016 - 12/2017

Wave Broadband, Kirkland, WA

Health Educator

03/2013 - 06/2015

Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA